A Finding Aid to the Paul Bransom Papers, 1862-1985, bulk 1904-1979, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
Paul Bransom papers
1862-1985
Archives of American Art
Bransom, Paul, 1885-
AAA.branpaul
Archival Resource Key
10.1 Linear feet
The papers of wildlife illustrator, painter, and cartoonist Paul Bransom measure 10.1 linear feet and date from 1862 to 1985. Almost half of the collection is comprised of Bransom's correspondence, which is particularly rich in documenting his early career as an illustrator, and his relationships with authors, art editors, and publishers from the 1900s to the 1940s. Correspondence also contains a wealth of cards, many of which bear reproductions or original artwork by his many artist friends. Also found in the papers are biographical essays, certificates and awards, memorabilia, writings and notes, business files, bibliographies, an artwork inventory, exhibition catalogs, clippings, printed illustrations, pamphlets, photographs, scrapbooks, and original artwork.
Provenance
The material on reel D254 was lent for microfilming in 1966, portions of which were subsequently donated along with additional papers by Bransom between 1972 and 1975, and by his nephew's wife, Althea Bond, in 1980. Mario Cesar Romero, identified by an AAA collector as the "Curator of the Bransom collection" and creator of an inventory of Bransom's artwork, donated additional materials to the Archives in 1983 and 1986, including printed materials, photographs, correspondence, records from the artwork inventory project, and scrapbooks. In 1985, James Zayicek donated 11 sketches and eight greeting cards via Helen Ireland Hays, a writer and a noted friend of Bransom's.
Separated Material
The Archives of American Art also holds microfilm of 17 items lent for microfilming (reel D254). Some of this material was later donated to the Archives, portions of which were then transferred to the Smithsonian American Art Museum/National Portrait Gallery Library and are available in their vertical file on Bransom. Loaned material is not described in this finding aid.
Related Material
The Archives of American Art holds the Helen Ireland Hays papers related to Paul Bransom, which contains 36 audio cassette recordings of Hays interviewing Bransom, among other materials. The Special Collections Division of the Stewart Library at Weber State College in Ogden, Utah holds the Paul Bransom Collection, a collection containing artwork, books from Bransom's personal library, manuscript material and photographs donated by Bransom in 1972 and 1974.
Restrictions on Access
The bulk of the collection has been digitized and is available online via AAA's website. Use of material not digitized requires an appointment.
Alternative Forms Available
The papers of Paul Bransom were digitized in 2007 by the Archives of American Art, and total 11397 images.
Duplicates, copies, certain printed materials, personal items of limited research value, and certain items related to others have not been digitized, as noted in the container listing.
Portions of the collection lent for microfilming are available on 35 mm microfilm reel D254 at the Archives of American Art offices and for interlibrary loan.
Biographical Note
Wildlife illustrator, painter, and cartoonist Paul Bransom was born in 1885 in Washington, D.C., and grew up sketching animals in his yard and at the National Zoo. He began work as a draftsman for the U.S. Patent Office at age 13, and went on to produce technical drawings for the Southern Railroad Co. and General Electric. He moved to New York City in 1903 and worked for the New York Evening Journal from 1904 to 1907, where he produced the comic "News from Bugville" and other cartoons. During this time, he befriended several New York artists in the cartoon trade, including James Swinnerton, Charles Sarka, T.S. Sullivant, Walt Kuhn, Rudy Dirks, and Gus Mager. He was a member of the Kit Kat Club and joined in their sketch classes and annual skelters. He sketched frequently at the New York Zoological Park, and was eventually invited by the director to use a room in the lion house as his studio. He married Grace Bond, an actress, in 1906.
Bransom's break as an illustrator came from art editor George Horace Lorimer of the Saturday Evening Post, who bought several of his drawings for Post covers around 1907. Bransom began illustrating animal stories regularly in magazines such as Delineator, Country Gentleman, An American Boy, Good Housekeeping, and Ladies Home Journal. In 1912, he illustrated a special edition Jack London's Call of the Wild, and soon after that, the first illustrated edition of The Wind in the Willows by Kenneth Grahame. During his career, Bransom illustrated 45 books and was a regular contributor to 35 magazines, illustrating works by popular writers such as Albert Payson Terhune, J. Frank Dobie, and Emma-Lindsay Squier. He also created animal scenes for advertisements.
In 1917, Bransom built a studio on Canada Lake, NY, in the Adirondacks and he and his wife split their time between the Canada Lake home and a winter apartment on 67th Street in New York City. In 1949, he bought a second summer home near Jackson Hole, Wyoming, in what is now the Grand Teton National Forest. In Wyoming, Bransom hosted artist friends and taught outdoor classes for the Teton Artists Associated until 1962, when his health forced him from the high altitudes back to Canada Lake, NY.
Bransom held his first solo exhibition in 1925 at Arden Gallery in New York City, and had at least 18 solo exhibitions around the country throughout his life, including at the Warren E. Cox Gallery (1929), Charles Scribner's Gallery (1935), the New York Zoological Park (1942), the Society of Illustrators (1942), the Denver Museum (1950), and the Woodmere Gallery in Philadelphia (1963). He often exhibited in the annual group exhibition of the Society of Animal Artists, a group he co-founded in 1960 and served as its second president, from 1968 until his death. Bransom was also a member of the American Watercolor Society, the American Artists' Professional League, the Salmagundi Club, the Dutch Treat Club, and the Boone and Crockett Club. In 1974 Bransom was granted an honorary Doctor of Art degree from Weber State College in Ogden, Utah. In 1975 he won the Benjamin West Clinedinst Memorial Medal for Distinguished Achievement in Painting.
Paul Bransom died in 1979 at the age of 94.
Scope and Content Note
The papers of wildlife illustrator, painter, and cartoonist Paul Bransom measure 10.1 linear feet and date from 1862 to 1985. Almost half of the collection is comprised of personal and professional correspondence. Also found in the papers are biographical essays, certificates and awards, memorabilia, writings and notes, business files, bibliographies, an artwork inventory, exhibition catalogs, clippings, printed illustrations, pamphlets, photographs, scrapbooks, and original artwork.
The correspondence is particularly rich in documenting Bransom's early career as an illustrator, and his relationships with authors, art editors, and publishers from the 1900s to the 1940s. Correspondence also contains a wealth of cards, many of which bear reproductions or original artwork by his many artist friends. Correspondence often bears notes made by Bransom about the correspondent. Further documentation of Bransom's career is found in Notes and Writings, including narrative writings and lists of artwork and contacts; and in Personal Business Records, which contain records of transactions with various clients and galleries, as well as bibliographies of works illustrated by Bransom, and an art inventory created posthumously by Mario Cesar Romero.
Printed materials include exhibition records, which are often annotated, and copies of Bransom's illustrations and cartoons as they appeared in print. Also found are clippings about Bransom and other artists he knew; newsletters, pamphlets, and other materials related to organizations with which he was involved; and a copy of his book on animal drawing technique. Photographs depict Bransom, his childhood and family, homes and studios, friends, travels, and other events. Many of the photographs bear identifications by Bransom. The collection has a voluminous Artwork series, which includes two sketchbooks and hundreds of original sketches, drawings, and designs by Bransom, as well as a series of prints and original artwork by others.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into 8 series:
Missing Title
Series 1: Biographical Material, circa 1862-1979 (Box 1, OV 12; 6 folders)
Series 2: Correspondence, circa 1903-1984 (Box 1-5; 4.5 linear feet)
Series 3: Notes and Writings, circa 1927-1973 (Box 5, OV 12; 0.2 linear feet)
Series 4: Personal Business Records, circa 1912-1981 (Box 5; 0.3 linear feet)
Series 5: Printed Materials, circa 1905-1985 (Boxes 6-7, OV 12; 1.5 linear feet)
Series 6: Photographs, circa 1885-1976(Boxes 7-8, 10; 1.3 linear feet)
Series 7: Scrapbooks, circa 1880s-1970s(Boxes 8 and 11; 0.5 linear feet)
Series 8: Artwork, 1903-1976 (Boxes 8-9, OV 13-22; 1.7 linear feet)
Greeting cards; Works of art; Sketchbooks; Animals in art; Painters -- New York (State) -- New York; Magazine illustration; Animal painters -- New York (State) -- New York; Art -- Economic aspects; Photographs; Scrapbooks; Illustrated letters
- Biographical Materials, circa 1862-1866, 1904, 1942-1979; Series 1; Archival Resource Key; 6 Folders Box 1, OV 12
  Scope and Contents note
  Biographical materials include notes, essays, and pamphlets and other ephemera related to Bransom's life and career. Also found are a passport, various awards, certificates of merit, and maps showing Bransom's property. A menu from the Café des Beaux Arts from New Year's Eve, 1904, is autographed by Bransom's artist friends, including J.D. Allen, Rudolph Dirks, F. Opper, James Swinnerton, Gus Mager, H.A. McGill, and T.S. Sullivant, among others. A file on Bransom's grandfather contains financial notes and receipts, an undated letter, and a newspaper item related to his death.
  Additional biographical notes and essays about other artists Bransom knew can be found in Notes and Writings.
  - Notes and Essays, 1976, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Printed Matter, 1963-1979, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - IDs, Awards, and Certificates, 1942-1979; Archival Resource Key; (See also OV 12) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Property, 1947, undated; Archival Resource Key; (See also OV 12) (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Autographed Menu, 1904; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - W.S. Bransom, Paul Bransom's Grandfather, 1862-1866, 1942, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Oversized Biographical Materials, Archival Resource Key; (See Box 1, f3-4) (Oversize 12)
- Correspondence, circa 1903-1984; Series 2; Archival Resource Key; 4.5 Linear feet Box 1-5
  This series includes personal and professional correspondence of Paul Bransom from the beginning of his career until the end of his life. Correspondence includes letters from other artists, art directors and editors, writers, nature and wildlife conservators and zoologists, curators, collectors, printers, engravers, family, and friends. Also found are letters Bransom wrote to his wife, Grace Bond Bransom, early in their relationship, and scattered correspondence to Grace Bond Bransom and Althea Bond, Bransom's niece and heiress. Many illustrated letters are found among the correspondence, including several lavishly illustrated letters from Charles Sarka. Photographs, clippings, and other enclosures such as membership cards, are scattered throughout the series.
  Correspondence is divided into three groups: that between Paul Bransom and his wife, general correspondence, and cards. General correspondence is arranged chronologically except for occasional instances where letters were originally grouped together by author or subject. Drafts and carbon copies of outgoing letters written by Paul Bransom are interfiled with general correspondence, and undated drafts are filed at the end of the general correspondence. Greeting cards with significant written messages are interfiled with general correspondence, and cards without messages are arranged alphabetically at the end of the series. Many of the cards are made with original artwork, as indicated in the folder notes below.
  General correspondence contains letters and records of transactions with Bransom's publishing clients, as well as letters from many authors whose stories Bransom illustrated, especially between the 1900s and the 1940s. Among the authors are Albert Payson Terhune, Donald Culross Peattie, J. Frank Dobie, Dorothy Cottrell, Attilio Gatti, Charmian London (wife of Jack London), and Herbert Sass. Artists represented in Bransom's correspondence include Charles Sarka, Joe Back, Walter Biggs, Patricia Bott, Chen Chi, John Clymer, Paul Fair, Charles Hargens, Bob Kuhn, Dorothy and Gertrude Lathrop, Bob Lougheed, George McLean, Ugo Mochi, Bill and Rachel Scott, Donald Teague, and Clarence Tillenius.
  Letters and envelopes are often annotated by Bransom giving the full name of the author and sometimes the nature of their relationship or other biographical information. Additional correspondence can be found in Personal Business Records, and some drafts of outgoing letters are found in the notebooks filed in Notes and Writings.
  See Appendix for a list of selected correspondents from Series 2.
  Appendix: Selected Correspondents from Series 2
  This selected index to Series 2: General Correspondence, includes selected artists, writers whose works Bransom illustrated, art editors and directors, collectors, printers and engravers, and other significant correspondents. Illustrated letters are indicated in parentheses. This index is not comprehensive.
  Agathon, Oshin: 1961, 1963
  Agins, Freddie: 1965, 1972 (illustrated letter), 1975, 1977
  Albee, Grace: 1961, 1967
  Aleshire, Morris: 1929 (illustrated letter)
  Alexander, Charles: 1923
  Astley-Bell (Duis), Rita: 1962-1963, 1973, 1976
  Ayres, Douglas: 1942, 1955, 1966-1967, 1971-1972, 1975-1976
  Back, Joe and Mary: 1959, 1961, 1963, 1965, 1967, 1971, 1979, undated
  Balch, Mr. and Mrs. Glenn: 1938-1939
  Bartholomew, C.L. "Bart": 1921
  Beal, Gifford: 1950, 1955
  Bellows, George: 1913
  Benda, W.T.: 1935, undated
  Biggs, Walter: 1938, 1944, 1966, 1967
  Blair, W. Reid: 1926, 1929, 1933
  Bott, Pat: 1964 (sketch), 1967-1971, 1973, 1983, undated
  Bowden, Harry: 1929
  Brand, Eva: 1972, undated
  Bull, Charles Livingston: 1931, 1933-1934
  Cady, Harrison: 1962, 1963
  Calfee, William: 1933
  Card, Helen Louise: 1950, 1954-1955, 1957, 1962
  Chaffee, Allan: 1931, 1932, 1937-1938, undated
  Chapin, J. H.: 1918-1920
  Chapin, James P.: 1942, 1945, 1963
  Chapman, Charles: 1931, 1934, 1960, undated
  Chi, Chen: 1953, 1957, 1958
  Clymer, John: 1964, 1970-1976, 1978-1979, undated
  Collett, Farrell R.: 1951, 1959-1960, 1964, 1969-1970, 1972, 1974, 1978, undated
  Cooper, Courtney Ryley; 1934
  Cooper, Frederic Taber: 1920
  Cottrell, Dorothy, 1931-1933
  Cox, Warren: 1977
  Crane, Alan H.: 1947, 1959-1962, 1967, undated
  Crowninshield, Frank: 1910
  Curwood, James Oliver: 1919
  DeFeo, Charles: 1969
  Delano, Gerard C.: 1957
  Dinsmore, Elizabeth: 1929, 1937-1940
  Dirks, Rudy: 1905 (2 illustrated envelopes)
  Dobie, J. Frank: 1926-1928, 1931, 1933, 1938-1939, 1945, 1962, undated
  Dower, Walter: 1922-1925, 1927-1928
  Drake, A.W.: 1907-1908
  Dwiggins, Clare Victor: 1950 (illustrated letter)
  Edge, Rosalie: 1937, 1939-1940, 1942, 1947, 1961-1962
  Eldridge, Paul: 1914 (illustrated letter)
  Enos, Ben H.: 1913
  Evans, George W. "Dub": 1928, 1945, 1961 (see also Notes and Writings, New Mexico Lion Hunt)
  Evans, Joe: 1928, 1945
  Fabian, Harold: 1958, 1973
  Fair, Paul: 1928-1929, 1931, 1939, 1945, 1948
  Field, Charles K.: 1914
  Folmsbee, Beulah: 1940
  Gannam, John: 1963
  Gatti, Attilio: 1941, 1944, 1947
  Gibson, "Pop": 1918-1919
  Gibson, Charles Dana: 1903, 1913
  Gilbert, Kenneth: 1925, 1928, 1945, 1972
  Godfrey, W.C.: 1929
  Goldman, Arthur: 1932
  Hagen, Grant: 1957, 1959, 1966, 1972
  Hahn Vidal, Margarita: 1963
  Hargens, Charles: 1970 (illustrated), 1971-1974, 1976, 1978
  Hays, Helen Ireland: 1963-1964, 1974-1975, 1977-1979, undated
  Hibben, Frank C. and Eleanor: 1945, 1972
  Hill, Maybel Betsy: 1933
  House, Brad: 1951, 1960, undated
  Howland, Karl V.S.: 1916-1917
  Hunt, Lynn Bogue: 1958
  Hurst, Dean: 1972, 1978
  Johnstone, Jo and Jack: 1945-1946, 1952, 1955, 1963, undated
  Kappel, Phillip: 1930, 1955
  Kent, Norman: 1963
  Kirkland, John W., Jr.: 1940
  Kuhn, Bob: 1936-1937, 1961, 1963, 1967, 1977-1978, undated
  Kuhn, Brenda: 1960-1961, 1967, 1971, 1984
  Kuhn, Vera: 1949
  Kuhn, Walt: 1905 (illustrated envelope), 1945
  Kylgaard, James: 1939
  Lathrop, Dorothy: 1939, 1942, 1954-1955, 1959, 1961-1964, 1966, 1969, 1971, 1974-1975, 1977, undated
  Lathrop, Gertrude: 1949, 1964, 1969, 1972-1973, 1978
  Lentelli, Leo and Mimi: 1955, 1956, 1962-1963
  Lewis, Martin: 1930
  Liljefors, Lindorm: 1969 (illustrated), 1970, 1974
  Lippincott, Joseph W.: 1933, 1945, 1954, 1975
  Logan, Maurice: 1929
  London, Charmian (Mrs. Jack London): 1913-1914
  Long, Ray: 1912
  Lougheed, Robert: 1963, 1965, 1967, 1969, 1971, undated
  MacCreagh, Gordon: 1935, undated (illustrated letter)
  Mattingly, Seth: 1955, 1961-1964, 1969-1970, 1972-1976 (with list of books), 1978, 1980-1981, 1983, undated
  McClintock, Dorcas: 1973, 1974-1978, 1980, undated
  McCoy, Garnett: 1966
  McCracken, Harold: 1948-1949, 1965, 1972
  McLean, George: 1964-1965, 1971, undated
  Means, Thomas H. and Constance: 1931, 1936, 1947, 1960, 1964
  Meigs, Ruth: undated
  Miller, George C.: 1949
  Mills, Dorothy: 1928
  Mochi, Ugo: 1963, 1967, 1969, 1971, 1973-1974, 1976, undated
  Moon, Carl: 1928
  Moore, Benson: 1939, 1941, 1945, 1959, 1964-1965, 1967, 1969, 1971-1974, undated
  Morris, George Ford: undated
  Moyle, Seth: 1911
  Murphy, Robert: 1940-1941
  Newell, Dave: 1942-1943 (illustrated letters), 1944-1945 (illustrated letter)
  Newett, Henry R.: 1927
  Nisbet, Bob: 1953-1954
  Olenchak, Tom: 1961, 1969, 1973, undated
  Osborn, Frederick and Margaret: 1930, 1940, 1954-1955, 1973, undated
  Palmer, Loren: 1926
  Peattie, Donald Culross: 1927, 1937
  Pierrot, George: 1927, 1932, 1934, 1937-1939, 1945, 1949, 1957, 1960-1963, 1967, 1969-1970, 1972-1979
  Platt, Joseph B.: 1926
  Richards, George M.: 1913
  Roosevelt, Mrs. Kermit: 1941
  Ruggles, C.B.: 1933
  Rutledge, Archibald: 1939-1940, 1949
  Sanborn, Elwin Roswell: undated
  Sarka, Charles: 1910 (illustrated envelope), 1911 (2 illustrated letters), 1913, 1917 (illustrated), 1934 (illustrated letter), 1941, 1947, 1948 (illustrated), 1950 (illustrated), 1958-1959
  Sass, Herbert R.: 1934-1936, 1940, 1942
  Saxton, Eugene: 1929
  Schaldach, William, 1946, 1958
  Schuler, Loring: 1919, 1927, 1931
  Schwiering, Connie: 1958, 1961, 1963, 1967
  Scott, William J. and Rachel: 1929, 1932-1933, 1956, 1964, 1967, 1973
  Scriver, Bob: 1962, 1965, 1967, undated
  Seimel, Sasha: 1933-1935, 1962-1963, 1967
  Sleicher, Bob: undated
  Sprunt, Alexander: 1932-1933
  Stahl, Ben: 1944, 1969, 1972
  Stokes, Frederick A.: 1921
  Stolper, Joel: 1940
  Stone, Walter King: 1933
  Taylor, E.H.: 1925-1927, 1930, undated
  Teague, Donald: 1970, 1972, 1975-1976
  Tee-Van, John: 1942
  Terhune, Albert Payson: 1926, 1927, 1929
  Thomas, J. Sharkey: 1974-1977
  Thompson, H.A.: 1907-1909
  Thurber, James: 1957
  Tillenius, Clarence: 1960, 1963, 1969, 1974, 1975-1978, 1981, undated
  Washington, Booker T.: 1915
  Watson, Ernest: 1951
  Weaver, John V.A.: 1928
  Wengenroth, Stow: 1962
  Williams, Wheeler: 1964, undated (illustrated letter)
  Wolfe, R. Dietz: 1961, 1963, 1964, undated
  Wood, Peggy: 1928
  - Letters of Introduction for Paul Bransom, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Letters from Paul Bransom to Grace Bond (Bransom), 1905-1908, 1926; Archival Resource Key; (3 folders) (Box 1, Folder 8-10)
    (Contains illustrated letters)
  - Notes Between Paul and Grace Bransom, 1942, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - General Correspondence, 1888, 1903-1909; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - General Correspondence, 1910-1911; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - General Correspondence, 1912-1913; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - General Correspondence, 1914-1916; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - General Correspondence, 1917; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - General Correspondence, 1918; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - General Correspondence, 1918-1920; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - General Correspondence, 1921, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - General Correspondence, 1922-1924; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - General Correspondence, 1925-1926, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - General Correspondence, 1926; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - General Correspondence, 1927; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - General Correspondence, 1928; Archival Resource Key; (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 24-25)
  - General Correspondence, 1929; Archival Resource Key; (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 26-27)
  - General Correspondence, 1930; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - General Correspondence, 1931; Archival Resource Key; (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 29-30)
  - General Correspondence, 1932; Archival Resource Key; (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 31-32)
  - General Correspondence, 1933; Archival Resource Key; (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 33-34)
  - General Correspondence, 1934; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - General Correspondence, 1935; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - General Correspondence, 1936; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - General Correspondence, 1937; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - General Correspondence, 1938; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - General Correspondence, 1938-1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - General Correspondence, 1939; Archival Resource Key; (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 41-42)
  - General Correspondence, 1940; Archival Resource Key; (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 43-44)
  - General Correspondence, 1941; Archival Resource Key; (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 45-46)
  - General Correspondence, 1942; Archival Resource Key; (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 47-48)
  - General Correspondence, 1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - General Correspondence, 1944; Archival Resource Key; (2 folders) (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
  - General Correspondence, 1945; Archival Resource Key; (2 folders) (Box 2, Folder 3-4)
  - General Correspondence, 1946; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - General Correspondence, 1947; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - General Correspondence, 1948; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - General Correspondence, 1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - General Correspondence, 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - General Correspondence, 1951-1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - General Correspondence, 1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - General Correspondence, 1954-1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - General Correspondence, 1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - General Correspondence, 1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - General Correspondence, 1957; Archival Resource Key; (2 folders) (Box 2, Folder 15-16)
  - General Correspondence, 1958; Archival Resource Key; (2 folders) (Box 2, Folder 17-18)
  - General Correspondence, 1959; Archival Resource Key; (2 folders) (Box 2, Folder 19-20)
  - General Correspondence, 1960; Archival Resource Key; (3 folders) (Box 2, Folder 21-23)